<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jon Rutishauser&#39;s Blog</title>
    <description>My name is Jon. This is where I’ll blog (and likely complain) as I learn JS, HTML, CSS and generally unravel the mysteries of the internets. 
</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 23:05:37 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 23:05:37 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Starting the Javascripts</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This week we at The Iron Yard we got started on JavaScript. The more I get into it, the more there seems to be to learn. I created a simple game of chess that can be launched via Node on our terminal command line. Basically, by creating a line of several arrays, “pieces” can be moved by writing a function that copies the piece at the occupied space to a new space and replaces the old piece with an empty space. Not that pretty to look at, but it was fun to mess around with and create something like a chess game while only knowing so little of a language. Each project helps me to solve various issues with a very limited tool bag of skills available to me. Can’t wait to see what I’ll pick up in in the next week. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 17:23:40 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/jekyll/update/2015/01/25/third-week.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/jekyll/update/2015/01/25/third-week.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Two Weeks Down!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s official, I’m two weeks in and the first blog post is up. No amount of discussion could have prepared me for the amount of work involved when starting The Iron Yard. I had some web experience from about a decade ago and spent the last few months using Code School, but I still find myself awake until two or three in the morning to add the final touches to each project. No matter how simple the project seems to be, there always seems to end up being some curve ball that needs to be solved to make each project presentable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this time, I have easily logged at least 160 hours of time on my laptop, frantically googling and using trial and error. I’ve been improving a lot on terminal and CSS with all the time I’ve put in, so I can’t wait to put those skills to use and get going on JavaScript. It’s awesome to learn about new tools such as Yeoman, HTML5 Boilerplate, Pretzo and Git with Github. The number of tools that are available to all developers at no cost is mind-blowing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After just two short weeks, it has become apparent how much more I have picked up, which at least makes the exhaustion and frustration seem worthwhile…most of the time, haha.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2015 17:23:40 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/jekyll/update/2015/01/11/two-weeks-down.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/jekyll/update/2015/01/11/two-weeks-down.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>HTML5 Boilerplate</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An interesting video about HTML5 Boilerplate&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/qyM37XKkmKQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2015 17:23:40 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/jekyll/update/2015/01/11/HTML5-boilerplate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/jekyll/update/2015/01/11/HTML5-boilerplate.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Tom&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &amp;#39;Hi, Tom&amp;#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll-help&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s dedicated Help repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2015 17:23:40 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/jekyll/update/2015/01/10/welcome-to-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/jekyll/update/2015/01/10/welcome-to-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
